#Encodergasm Presents
～
（ジェット）でな そのカメは―
And so, the turtle took him to a place called Ryuuguujou as a reward.
お礼に やつを竜宮城ってとこに
連れていったんだ
Ryuuguujou?
（エド）竜宮城？
Yeah.  At that palace, they held a welcome party for him.
そうよ
その城では歓迎のパーティーを
やってくれてな
Beautiful women, and scrumptious feasts.
きれいな姉ちゃんに豪華な食事
タイやヒラメが舞い踊り―
Breams and halibut swam about...
...and so he spent his time as if in a dream.
夢のような時が過ぎてくわけよ
I see...
おおーお
I haven't eaten breams or halibut in quite a while...
（スパイク）タイもヒラメも
久しく食ってねえなあ
Days passed before he knew it, and when he was about to go back...
あっという間に日は過ぎて
いざ やつが帰るとき―
...he was given the Tamatebako as a souvenir.
土産にと渡されたのが玉手箱
Tamatebako?  Is that yummy?
玉手箱？ それ おいしい？
食いもんじゃねえよ
中に お宝が入った箱だ
It's not food.  It's a chest with treasure inside.
I haven't seen any treasure in quite a while either...
お宝も久しく拝んでねえな
You guys are so tasteless.  This is an old fantasy tale!
即物的なやつらだな 全く
昔のファンタジーなんだよ これは
The turtle's Tamatebako...
（エド）カメの玉手箱
はあ　何を聞いてんだ
What were you listening to?
（フェイ）あーあ
I should quit the horses now.
もう馬は やめよう
いっしょっと ん
Pay up 6300 woolongs.
6300ウーロン払えよ
何よ やぶから棒に
What, where did that come from?
This was for you.
（ジェット）
お前宛てに届いたんだよ
私宛て？
For... me?
C.O.D.  Even.
（ジェット）着払いでな
（フェイ）うっ
To top it off, no return address.
おまけに差出人不明だ
仕方なしに受け取っといて
やったんだからな
I had no choice but to accept it...
H-Hey!  Wait!!
お？ おい 待て
HEY!  What about the 6300 woolongs?!
おおい 6300ウーロン
Busy woman.
（スパイク）忙しい女だね
Could it be a collection agency from the life extension firm?
まさか延命会社の取り立て屋？
それとも…
Or...
No, could it be...
いやあ ひょっとして…
Oooh...  I just have too many things it could be...
ああ もう
思い当たる節がありすぎて…
So for now, I'll just run away!
とりあえず 逃げとこう
Don't you think it's fishy?
（ジェット）怪しいと思わねえか？
For a woman who always claims other people's property...
人のものでも
自分のものだって言う女が―
...as her own to run away without even touching it?
触りもせずに逃げるなんてよ
She seems to have picked up a lot of grudges from all over, though.
恨みは あちこちで
買ってそうだしな
（ジェット）うん　一応―
I should do an explosives test and a biochemical test just in case...
爆発物反応と
バイオケミカル反応を調べてと…
No!
いや やっぱり宅配会社に返品して
立て替えた金を返してもらうのが…
I should return this to the courier service...
...and have them refund the money I paid for her sake.
お お お おおお おおお…
Hey, Spike!
おい スパイク
（スパイク）ん？
What the hell is this?
何だ こりゃ？
Does it make any ticking noises?
時計の音とかは してないのか？
Nope.
（スパイク）ああ
I got data!
（エド）出ーたよー
（ジェット）ん？
Data from the courier service!
宅配会社のデータ
The sender is...
（ジェット）差出人は
“エウロパの慈善修道院”？
...a nonprofit nunnery in Europa?!
There's more...
（エド）まだ あるよ
（ジェット）ん？
Pluto Prison?
“冥王星刑務所”
Asteroid Actors' Studio?
“アステロイド･
アクターズスタジオ”
Fourth Uranus Observatory?
“天王星第４観測所”
Venus News Network?
“ビーナスニュースネットワーク”
Forwarded, forwarded, and forwarded some more...
転送 転送 また転送
This thing's been passed around the entire solar system...
太陽系中たらい回しだな
（エド）ほり
Here.
Due to the explosion of the Lunar Gate, all data from before 2022 has been lost.
（ジェット）
“月ゲート爆発事故により―”
“2022年以前のデータは消失”
An antique.
年代もんだな
（ジェット）どうやら
“ビデオテープ”ってやつらしい
It seems to be something called a videotape.
An artifact of the good old days.
古き良き時代の遺物ってやつだ
（スパイク）ふうん
She's the one that ran away.
（ジェット）
勝手に逃げちまったんだ
She has no right to complain even if we sell it off.
売られても文句は言えんだろう
You think it will sell?
（スパイク）売れるかねえ
They say he's a maniac when it comes to 20th century images...
（ジェット）20世紀映像の
マニアだってんだから 買うさ
I'm sure he'll buy it.
（スパイク）
値打ちもんとは思えねえが
I just don't think this is worth anything.
The real worth of treasures like this can't be determined from the outside.
（ジェット）
こういうお宝の価値ってのは
見た目じゃ分からねえもんだ
You may be surprised at how much you can sell it for!
案外 すげえ値が
ついたりするもんよ
I need to get enough to cover the C.O.D.  Charges at least.
せめて着払い分は回収しねえとな
ごめんよ
Excuse me!
So...
（妹）だから…
（ビデオマニア）静かに
QUIET!
Everything about this city is different from Minnesota, where we were before.
（妹）この町は 何もかもが
私たちのいたミネソタとは違うわ
Hey, brother, are you sure we can get along well here?
ねえ兄貴 本当にあたしたち
ここでうまくやっていけるのかしら
Mm...  To tell the truth, I wasn't so sure that we could.
（兄）ん… 本当はちょっと
自信なくしてたんだけど…
But, I'm sure we'll be all right.
でも大丈夫さ
Because I'm here with my twin sister.
双子の妹と一緒だからな
フッ ありがとう 兄貴
Thanks, brother.
Oh man, I have to work in the morning!
（兄）やれやれ
明日も朝からバイトだよ
（妹）おやすみ 兄貴
（兄）おやすみ
Good night, brother.
Good night!
（ビデオマニア）くああ いい
GOD, that's good!  Drama series from the 20th century are so good!
やっぱ20世紀のドラマはいいわー
On the other hand...  Drama series as of late are so...
それに引き換え
最近のドラマときたら
全く…
I have something you want to watch...
あんたに
見てもらいたいもんが…
（ビデオマニア）おあー！
Hey, hey, hey, you can't do that!
おいおいおい  駄目だよ あんた
（スパイク）ん？
The cigarette, man, the cigarette!
たばこだよ  たばこ
Don't you know that smoke can totally screw up electrical appliances?
煙が電子部品を狂わすってことも
知らないのか？
Sheesh, this is why I hate people who don't know...
全く これだから素人は もう～
どあああああー
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot!  SHEESH!
ばかばかばかばか
全く もう…
What the hell do you guys want?!
あんたら一体 何なの？
何の恨みが？
What do you have against me?!
No grudges, but no gratitude, either.
恨みも恩もねえよ
I just have something we want you to buy from us.
買ってもらいたいもんが
あるだけだ
Ah!  Is that a Beta cassette?!
おっ ベータじゃないか  すっげえ
That's amazing!
Where did you get a hold of this?
どこで手に入れたんだ？
これ 掘り出しもんだぜ あんた
This is a true find, mister!
It's close to a miracle that this thing exists in one piece!
現存するだけでも
奇跡に近い代物だよ
Beta?
“ベータ”？
ん 知らないの？
You don't know what this is?
Oh, all right, do you want me to explain?
しょうがないな 教えてあげようか
えー 20世紀の頃はね
Back in the 20th Century, they didn't use disks like we do to record movies.
映像を記録するのに
今みたいなディスクじゃなくて―
They used things called video tapes, which are in cassettes like this.
こういうカセットに入った
ビデオテープってのを使ってたのよ
It's not digital!  It's analog!
デジタルじゃないんだぜ
アナログなんだ
And to top it off, it's magnetic...  Yeah, magnetic!
しかも磁気だぜ 磁気
They were recording with electromagnetic signals!  Ain't that amazing?
磁気信号に記録してたわけさ
すげえだろ
だけど開発してた
メーカーの違いで―
But a disagreement between the companies who created...
ベータとＶＨＳって
２つの規格ができちまってね
...this technology resulted in two standards, Beta and VHS.
Beta had a small cassette for their day...
ベータっていうのは―
この頃にしちゃ
カセットが小さいから―
...and the playback decks were compact and didn't take much space.
デッキもコンパクトで
場所を取らなくてさ
スチルやスローなんかの
特殊再生のときにも―
You didn't get that much noise when using the special...
...replay features like still frame and slow motion.
ノイズが入らないし しかも！
ベータ版は画像もきれいだから―
And, because Beta had high quality images...
映像志向のユーザーには
絶大な支持を受けたんだ  けど…
...users who were into good graphics supported it really heavily.
But, there begins the unfortunate history of the Beta tape.
そっからがベータの不幸な歴史の
始まりだったんだ
You don't need to tell me.
能書きは もういい
え？ まだ ほんのイントロだよ
This is just the introduction!
（ジェット）
こっちの用件は言っただろう
I told you what we wanted.
So how is it?  Are ya gonna buy it?
どうなんだ？ 買うのか？
ヘッヘヘ
Well, that depends on what's on it...
ま 中身次第だね
（ジェット）ん？
（ビデオマニア）
あらららららららら
Hey, what's wrong?
おお どうした？
It's so hard to adjust the tracking for these early Beta tapes...
いや トラッキングが
合いにくいのが―
この初期型ベータの特徴でね
This way?
こっちかな？
いや こっちかな　んん
Or this way?
にゃあら テープがかんだ　ん
It's eating the tape!
ひいっ
It's not getting any better...
（ジェット）直らねえな
あら？
It's coming...
来た… ああ 来た
It is...  It is...
I got it!
来た
うわっはー　ウフ
やっぱり馬より犬ね
Dogs are better than horses after all!
Most things get better if I kick 'em.
（スパイク）大抵は
蹴飛ばしゃ直るんだけどな
You just don't know when to quit.
大体 お前は
加減ってものを知らないんだよ
（ジェット）ん？
弁償しろ 俺のデッキ
Dammit, repay me for breaking my deck!
You again...
また お前か
You broke someone else's valuable machinery...
人の貴重な機械 壊しといて
責任 取らないつもりか？
...and you're not going to take responsibility for it?!
And how are you going to take responsibility for our valuable tape?
こっちの貴重なテープの責任は
どう取ってくれるんだよ
初期型ベータは
テープをかみやすいんだよ
Early Beta decks often eat tapes!
In any case, I'll have you pay for the repair costs!
とにかく 修理代は
払ってもらうからな
テープの代償でちゃらだ
We'll call it even with the cost of the tape!
WHAT?!  Be...
何を ベー…
Sheesh...
全く
（エド）ベータのデッキ
いらっしゃーい
Hello, Beta deck!
There's just one of those.
１個だけあったよ
Where is this?
ここは どこでしょう
旧アジアの地下都市
電気博物館？
The Underground City Electrical Museum in old Asia?
I'm going to figure out what's on that tape at any cost!
（ジェット）
よーし こうなったら意地でも
何が映ってるか確かめてやる
（スパイク）
そこまで入れ込むようなもんか？
Is it really something worth all the trouble?
（フェイ）来た来た来た来た
It's coming...  It's...  It's...  It's...
よーし 来たー
YEAH!  I got it!!
ほーんと 私の運って―
Really, I wonder if those guys were sucking up all my luck all this time.
今まで あいつらに
吸い取られてたんじゃないの？
（フェイ）はーい　もしもーし
Ah...  Hello.
Hello?
もしもし？ あれ？
おーい　もしもしー
Hey, helllllloooooo...
ああ フェイだ　やっほーい
Ah... it's...  Faye...  Yoohoo...
Wait...  Hello?
ちょっと もしもし？
何よ これ 今どこ？
What is this, where are you guys?
地球
Earth...
（フェイ）ん？
地球
Earth!
（フェイ）地球？
Earth?!
Wait a minute, you guys left me behind to go that far away...
ちょっと 私を置いて
勝手に そんな遠くへ…
（エド）スパイクとジェットがね
Spike... and Jet...
ああ…
（ジェット）
よーし もうすぐだ
All right, just a little longer.
Is there really one left in a place like this?
本当に残ってんのか？
こんなとこに
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
虎穴に入らずんば虎児を得ずだ
（ジェット）地下28階か
28th underground floor.
（ジェット）動かねえか？
It's not moving?
The cable broke, so it's stuck.
（ジェット）ケーブルが切れて
引っ掛かってやがるな
（スパイク）えい
（ジェット）ええい
（ジェット）ん？
（スパイク）うわっ なあっ
（ジェット）うわあ！
（スパイク）うっ うう… んん…
うう…
なんでこんな目に遭ってんだ？
俺たちは
Why are we going through all of this?
It just means that treasure-hunting isn't easy.
宝探しは
楽には いかねえってことさ
宝？ 宝ってのは何だっけな
Treasure?
What was the treasure we were after?
玉手箱だろ
The Tamatebako, was it?
I kinda see why the man turned into an...
玉手箱を開けて―
男がじじいになった訳が
何となく分かるな
...old geezer after opening the Tamatebako now.
（スパイク）
いまさら引き返しても若返らねえぜ
Even if we head back now, we're not gonna be any younger.
This is some Ryuuguujou...
とんだ竜宮城だぜ
大体 あの女は
一体どこ行ったんだ？
Where DID that broad go in the first place?!
It's coming...  It's, it's...
（フェイ）来た来た来た… きっ
（フェイ）ああ…
（観客）よっしゃー
Oh well, nothing I could've done.
ま しょうがない
どうせ勝負は時の運ってね
Races are all luck anyway.
（スパイク）ここか？
（ジェット）ここだな
Is it here?
It's here.
All right.
（スパイク）よし
これか？
Is this it?
Yeah, that's gotta be it.
（ジェット）ああ 間違いねえ
And?
（スパイク）
で？ どれ持っていくよ？
Which one are we taking back?
（ジェット）ああ そうだな
Let's see...
Well, bigger is always better, they say.
大は小を兼ねるだ
（ジェット）ん？
（スパイク）どした
What's wrong?
（ジェット）なんか大きさが…
（スパイク）大丈夫だろう
The size...
Isn't it all right?
It's not going in.
（ジェット）入んねえぞ
（スパイク）押し込めよ
Force it in.
（ジェット）しかし…
But...
Ah!  That's not it!
ああ それ違うよ
（スパイク･ジェット）ああ？
（エド）ＶＨＳだから
That's VHS, so...
（スパイク･ジェット）はあ？
...you can't see the tape!
見れないのー
（スパイク･ジェット）はあ？
（フェイ）ああ もしもし？
私だけど
Oh, hello, it's me.
（エド）
アイン 誰とお話ししてるの？
Ein, who are you talking to?
Oh, it's Faye!
ああ フェイだ
I'm glad there's an organism there that I can talk to.
よかったわ
言葉の通じる生き物がいて
What is it?
（エド）何ですかー？
Was there anyone who went there to visit me?
お客は来なかった？ 私に
Visitors?
お客？ うーん…
（フェイ）怖いおじさんとか
Like scary middle-aged guys.
You know, guys that scream stuff like...
“金返せ”とか
“逮捕する”なんて叫ぶ人とかよ
..."gimme back my money!" Or "You're under arrest!"?
Yeah there was one.
うん  来たよ
Eh?  And?
え それで？
Something about repay him, even with tape munch, munch and grind, bye-bye!
（エド）弁償しろ～の
テープ かみかみ～の
ちゃらのつもりで
くりくりばいばいしたよー
Eh?  Okay...
え？ あ そう　まあいいや
Oh, well.
Where's Spike and Jet?
スパイクとジェットは？
Disappointed and zoned out.
がっくりで ぼーっとしてる
あっ そうなの？
I see...  Hmm...
ふうん
そうなんだ  そっか…
That's how...
Oh, well.
じゃあ ま しょうがない
If they're so lonely without me, I guess I have no choice.
私がいなくて
そんなに寂しがってるなら―
I'm coming back!
帰ってやるか
What?!  Another package for that broad?!
（ジェット）
なにぃ？ また あの女の荷物？
I won't accept it!  Take it and go back!!
受け取り拒否だ  持ち帰ってくれ
（ジェット）ああ！
（スパイク）ん？
Shit, why do I have to pay for HER C.O.  D?!
くそお なんで
あの女の着払いを…
しかも一度ならず二度までも
And not once, but TWICE!
You sure are persistent.
しつこい性格のやつだな
あ…
A Beta!
（エド）ベータだ
We can see the tape with this?
（スパイク）
これ 見られるやつか？
（エド）うん
Yeah.
Hey guys, long time no see.
はーい　旦那方 ご無沙汰
（エド）できたよー
It's done.
Hold up.
待った
（フェイ）ん？
If you're going to watch...
（ジェット）見るなら
着払い金 合計 税込みで―
...pay back the C.O.D.  Charges.  With tax, a total of 31,500 woolongs.
３万１千と500ウーロン
いただきます
ふん　結構でございます　んっ
Oh, fine.
ふん
（スパイク）おっ
（ジェット）映った
We have something!
（エド）おおー これ なーに？
Ooooh... what's this?
Shut up and watch.
（ジェット）黙って見てろ
（少女時代のフェイ）ええと…
Um...  Everyone decided to...
みんなで…
それぞれ10年後の自分に―
...send a message to themselves ten years in the future.
メッセージを
送ることにしました
Oh, come on, don't laugh!
やだ ちょっと笑わないの
ん…
Um...
ええっと
アハハ　なんかこれ
やっぱ照れるよ…
This makes me blush after all!
Eh?  Something I want to say?
え 言いたいこと？
う うーん…
うーん  おはよう
Good morning...
あっ 今のなし
Oh!  Nevermind!
（鳥のさえずり）
Good morning, me.
（少女時代のフェイ）
おはよう あたし
Did you sleep well?
よく眠れた？
そして よく目覚めた？
And did you wake up well?
光も風も空気も においも―
Does the light and the wind, the air and the smell, all feel brand new?
みんな真新しく
感じられていますか？
体の細胞１つ１つ
目覚めていますか？
Is each and every cell in your body awake now?
今日は今日の新しいあなた
Today, you are who you are today.
新しい あたしなんだよ
You are a newer version of me.
10年後のあたしなんて―
Myself ten years from now.
今のあたしには遠すぎて
全然 想像がつかない
That's so far away for me that I can't even begin to imagine.
Am I alone?
あたしは１人？
それとも 誰かすてきな人が
そばにいますか？
Or is there a wonderful person next to me?
Well, knowing me, I'm sure I am troubling a lot of different people.
まあ あたしのことだから―
きっとまた いろんな人に
迷惑をかけてることでしょう
But that's all right.  There's no problem.
でも平気  問題ないよ
あたしは必ず
あなたを応援している
I will always be cheering you on.
And now for a big cheer, from the bottom of my heart.
では エールを  心から
フレーッ フレーッ
Go!  Go!
Me, me, me!
Do your best, do your best!  Me, me, me!
頑張れ 頑張れ
負けるな 負けるな
Don't lose, don't lose!  Me, me, me!
（少女時代のフェイ）
フレーッ フレーッ
（フェイ）分からない
（少女時代のフェイ）
フレーッ フレーッ
I don't know...
（少女時代のフェイ）
フレーッ フレーッ
あ た し！
（フェイ）思い出せない
I can't remember...
（少女時代のフェイ）
頑張れ 頑張れ あ た し！
（フェイ）これは… 私？
Is this... me?
（少女時代のフェイ）
あたしは もう ここにはいない
I am no longer here.
But I'm here today, and I'll always be cheering for you right here.
でも この日のあたしは―
ずっと ここから
あなたを応援している
Cheering for you, my only self.
たった一人のあたしへ
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（スパイク）なんか―
You know, I'm starting to get tired of us doing all the previews like this.
俺たちがこう 予告をやるって
パターンも飽きてきたな
Once in a while, can't we have someone else...
（スパイク）
お お ちょうどいいな
Oh?  Oh!  You're perfect.  All right!
よし 今回は お前がやってみろ
Here, you try doing it this time.
（スパイク）へえ～
（スパイク）あ そうなんだ
Oh!  So, THAT'S how it is!
（スパイク）
ああ そりゃ面白そうだわ
Wow, this is going to be an interesting episode!
（アイン）
次回「ワイルド･ホーセス」
Next Episode: Wild Horses.
（スパイク）あ しゃべった
Hey, it spoke!